<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>jaredStef Blog</title>
    <description>{&quot;A blog about a programmer&quot;=&gt;nil}</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 23:22:44 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 23:22:44 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      
      <item>
        <title>San Francisco Type</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;Typographically speaking 2015 was huge for Apple. The first type it has made in over 20 years, known as San Francisco (and San Francisco Compact for those checking), was finally shipped to the public found first in the Apple Watch, and later in OSX 10.11 El Capitan, iOS 9, tvOS, and the new keyboards introduced in 2015. Most end-users wont notice the difference, but a typography geek like me completely does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;San Francisco is a neo-grotesque san-serif type fitting in the same category as the previously used Helvetica Neue. Incase you don&amp;#39;t work at a type foundry or aren&amp;#39;t a typography geek like me let me let me break it down for you. Sans serif fonts are fonts which do not contain serifs. A serif is a line finishing the strokes of a letter. In layman terms they are the little lines that overlap the tips of the letters. Neo-grotesque is a modern design style of type which has evolved from the grotesque style. Again in layman terms just a modern style of type. Apple created the font to address concern and complains made about the readability of Helvetica Neue at small sizes or on non-retina displays (used with OS X).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;San Francisco Type&quot; src=&quot;/assets/img/SF_Reg.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With readability being the clear goal in mind during the creation of San Francisco the subtile curves of Helvetica in glyphs such as &amp;#39;G&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;a&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;1&amp;#39;, and &amp;#39;7&amp;#39; have been replaced with straight lines. It is a bit blockier as well especially in it&amp;#39;s compact form (Keeping in mind that it it&amp;#39;s purpose is for displays and not print). To describe it in a sentence it is a cross between &amp;quot;Univers&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot; optimized for readability. While I still prefer Helvetica Neue the readability at small sizes or on low ppi displays is better. Unfortunately to get there Apple did make a tradeoff. Was it worth it? I believe so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt = &quot;Helvetica Neue Type&quot; src=&quot;/assets/img/HN_Reg.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early in Apple&amp;#39;s history it was at the forefront of digital typography, but in recent years it has slipped with other companies such as Google, and Mozilla creating their own type. It is nice to see Apple creating type once again, and I look foreward to the possibility of them creating more in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;Typographically speaking 2015 was huge for Apple. The first type it has made in over 20 years, known as San Francisco (and San Francisco Compact for those checking), was finally shipped to the public found first in the Apple Watch, and later in OSX 10.11 El Capitan, iOS 9, tvOS, and the new keyboards introduced in 2015. Most end-users wont notice the difference, but a typography geek like me completely does.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/SanFranciscoVHelvetica/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/SanFranciscoVHelvetica/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>The Ultimate Linux Distro #2</title>
        <description>&lt;h3&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my last post I spoke about my quest to find the ultimate Linux distro. It seemed that my biggest concern for the distro is the desktop environment, so I tried 4 different desktops since then all running on the latest version of Ubuntu (except Bungie). All desktops where tested in their latest versions at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Gnome&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;KDE&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Xubuntu&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Xubuntu is a&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Do Bungie in final one&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;h3&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my last post I spoke about my quest to find the ultimate Linux distro. It seemed that my biggest concern for the distro is the desktop environment, so I tried 4 different desktops since then all running on the latest version of Ubuntu (except Bungie). All desktops where tested in their latest versions at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/UltimateLinuxDistro2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/UltimateLinuxDistro2/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>The Ultimate Linux Distro #1</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;I love linux. It&#39;s open source and the most customizable OS on the planet. From a purely technical kernel aspect Linux is my favorite OS. Well then why don&#39;t I use it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Prologue&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before getting a Mac and switching to OS X in August of 2014, I used Linux; Ubuntu (Unity) to be more precise. It was better than Windows and a *nix OS. I like the ideologies of Linux and what it stands for, but just can&amp;#39;t find myself to use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Productivity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am big on the fact that tools should enhance productivity, not hinder it. Everyone is different and thus what works best for everyone is different. Currently for me it is the Mac. I don&amp;#39;t use Windows. It isn&amp;#39;t *nix based and causes me to waste time on pointless tedious things that no end-user should have to deal with. This blog post isn&amp;#39;t a rant about Windows however, it is one about me and my quest to find the ultimate Linux distro for me. I like the fact that on my Mac all of the tool bars are at the top. It is one less thing that I have to think about and remember on a per-application basis. Spotlight allows me to quickly launch apps without even touching a mouse, and tools like ShortCat allow me to use the mouse even less. The dock is convent for storing applications I frequently use and gets out of my way when I&amp;#39;m not using it. I like that. If I want to do something then I just do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;User Experience&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I absolutely love a great user experience. Using a computer should be intuitive, precognitive, and actually a pleasure to use. I am also a perfectionist. I will notice that one pixel that is off or the slightest inconsistency. The UX use has to meet all of these expectations and so far I have not found a Linux desktop that meets them. All are either too complex for everyday use, ugly, or just don&amp;#39;t give you the feeling that what you are looking at is meaningful. While I am not huge on the new design of OS X Yosemite it is still the best out there in comparison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Goal of this Blog Series&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok Jared. You just said that you love Linux and then tore it apart and threw it in the trash. What is the point? The point is that in this blog series I will try to find the Linux distro that works best for me and explain what I do or do not like. If you have any recommendations please leave them in the comments below.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What I am looking for in a Distro&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The distro I want needs to be beautiful, have good window management, nothing on the desktop, and a way for me to quickly launch applications using only the keyboard or a dock that looks nice and can be hidden. Having the menus in a menubar would be nice, but I can get over it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;I love linux. It&#39;s open source and the most customizable OS on the planet. From a purely technical kernel aspect Linux is my favorite OS. Well then why don&#39;t I use it?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/UltimateLinuxDistro1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/UltimateLinuxDistro1/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>What IDE should I use?</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;What IDE should I use? Should I buy a Mac? What Linux distro/desktop are you using? I&#39;m sure you have all heard the same questions before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As programmers we tend to get caught up in what tools we are using. &amp;quot;Oh he uses Eclipse? He must be a terrible coder. Who uses that?&amp;quot;. We&amp;#39;ve all heard it, seen it, or have even thought it. Even if you don&amp;#39;t know the thousands of key-combos and code generation features in IntelliJ Idea you will use it. Guess what? It doesn&amp;#39;t matter what IDE you use. You could use notepad on a computer running Windows 2000! What matters is the code, not the window it is in. You should use whatever tools you are most productive with, because ultimately tools are supposed to help you become more productive, not less. In this post I will list the tools that I use when coding and how they make me the most productive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Atom&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Atom is a text editor from Github that is really customizable. You can change not just the theme, but the modules installed, key maps, and complete layout. I use this when I want to code in a language I am good at and not have anything get in my way. It is also good for editing markup (like these blog posts :D). I could write a whole post on the customization options. It is hackable to the core and is open source. If something is there that gets in your way - remove it. With it hitting version 1.0 recently adoption has peaked and I have seen many sublime users switch over and in my opinion it is a valid choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Xcode&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use Xcode because I don&amp;#39;t have much of a choice. It is the official IDE for iOS and I&amp;#39;m not convinced on App Code. The navigation system is unique with a bar across the top allowing quick file navigation, and class definitions/documentation is only a click away. Interface builder provides a nice solid way of building interfaces using storyboard files. The IDE does lack several features I&amp;#39;ve come accustom to, but it gets the job done. The app is OS X only, which I completely understand from Apples perspective, but it would be nice to have on Linux.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;IntelliJ, Netbeans, and Eclipse (Oh My)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially when I started learning Java, listening to Buckey Roberts on youtube I downloaded Eclipse. It was a good choice for beginners. (Although for beginners I would personally recommend Netbeans) I later switched to Netbeans. It was just easier to use and I found myself not having to worry about tedious things like I had to in Eclipse. It made me more productive and allowed me to focus on my code more. It also had Java FX support first and was made by Oracle so was the first to support new Java features. In September of 2014 a friend of mine recommended IntelliJ Idea to me. I was quite satisfied with Netbeans, but I tried it out none the less. The automatic code completion, and setup was quite nice. The folks at IntelliJ have made a good IDE with many useful features. The problem is just finding all of them! While my productivity certainly hasn&amp;#39;t jumped enormously when switching the many features come in handy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Vim and Emacs (The holy war)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I honestly don&amp;#39;t use either yet. One day I will learn them, but until then I am fine with Atom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We must remember that with all the options out there for text editors and IDE&amp;#39;s the core focus of the code must not change. In sports they say &amp;quot;The glove doesn&amp;#39;t make the player, the player makes the glove.&amp;quot; In programming I say &amp;quot;The IDE isn&amp;#39;t definitive of the programmer, the code is.&amp;quot; It doesn&amp;#39;t have the same ring to it, but is true none the less. The title of this blog should have been &amp;#39;It&amp;#39;s all about the code&amp;#39;. Because at the end of the day the breakthrough algorithm in your code will make you, not the fact that you used Vim over Emacs. (I&amp;#39;m sorry I just had to mention that whole holy war ;) )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To end this off I figured you could use a laugh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/real_programmers.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;What IDE should I use? Should I buy a Mac? What Linux distro/desktop are you using? I&#39;m sure you have all heard the same questions before.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/IDEs/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/IDEs/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Diversity In Tech</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;In tech these days a big focus has been on diversity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your company doesn&amp;#39;t have enough women, or african-americans working there than shame on you. There are many programs and grants to try and get women and african-americans into tech. Why? People say that these companies are discriminatory because they are consisted of dominantly white males. To make sure I looked up the definition and this is what I found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Discrimination&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Treatment or consideration based on class or category rather than individual merit; partiality or prejudice&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If companies were hiring the majority of white males because they were white males than that would be discrimination. However, if they hired 10 of the best qualified workers that HAPPEN to be white males then that is not. I am tired of  many recent programs which try to increase the percentage of a particular ethnic/racial group in tech. Are they choosing people for say a grant based on whether they are the most eager to learn or have the most challenges to overcome; or is it because they are a women? (I don&amp;#39;t mean to pick on women. Any other group would suffice) They are choosing the individual because they are the category of the female sex. Read the definition above. You are looking at discrimination. When I start a company and we hire 10 people at the end of the day we would have 10 of the most qualified people. Not 10 women, men, african-americans, asians or otherwise. I would have 10 human beings. That is how I look at it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;In tech these days a big focus has been on diversity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/DiversityInTech/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/DiversityInTech/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>My Thoughts On WWDC</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;As you may (or may not) know, WWDC was on the 10th and introduced many new interesting things for both developers and users. I don&#39;t go super in depth on Swift 2.0 and all the new developer stuff, because that will be covered in my next blog post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/osx/elcapitan-preview/&quot;&gt;OS X&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;End User Features&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next version of OS X &amp;#39;El Capitan&amp;#39; was announced at WWDC. The release is to focus on performance and experience. The OS features a new split view mode which allows you to run two apps side-by-side in full screen. I feel like this will be useful on MacBooks in particular and can defiantly see myself using the feature. The OS is a lot snappier with speed improvements across the board. There are a lot of small features and it seems like Apple is trying to fix some of the many flaws OS X Yosemite had. The design is basically unchanged which disappoints me. I wasn&amp;#39;t a fan of OS X Yosemite&amp;#39;s new design completely and was hoping that Apple would fix most of it. Looks like it&amp;#39;s here to stay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Power User/Dev features&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to make the system a lot faster Apple had to make some under the hood changes. Apple is bringing Metal, it&amp;#39;s openGL/openCL like replacement to the Mac. Announced last year for iOS, Metal reduces the overhead between the hardware and software allowing for dramatic performance improvements. Core Animation and Core Graphics are now going to run on top of this. Graphics performance is especially important on Macs because most of them have integrated GPU&amp;#39;s and many pro creative customers create on the Mac. Many Mac users are reporting increased VRAM under the &amp;#39;About My Mac&amp;#39; menu. There is a new rootless option in the boot arguments by default which removes the ability to use the terminal as root. This may be a sound security measurement for the average user, but for developers and pro users this is horrible. You can currently change it using a command, but it is a pain. I believe in the final release you will have to boot into recovery mode and then change the setting under some advanced options. Like I said above the design is mostly unchanged except for the addition of a new default system font, San Fransisco. This font originally debuted in the Apple Watch as &amp;#39;San Fransisco Condensed&amp;#39;. The goal is to improve legibility, an area Helvetica Neue wasn&amp;#39;t particularly well at on non-retina displays. I am not a Mac Developer so I can&amp;#39;t go as in depth with advanced features as I can with iOS. A public beta will be available in July.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/ios/ios9-preview/&quot;&gt;iOS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple announced a lot in terms of iOS, but I&amp;#39;ll be brief. The iPad now has a new split window mode, the app switcher looks different, and there is a new News app. The news app is basically an attempt to sherlock Flipboard. I have not used it yet however, so I can&amp;#39;t comment on how well it does. Siri is better and spotlight is now more intelligent. No single feature is mind blowing, but the small changes and subtle optimizations will improve the way you use your iOS device for sure. (The system font is San Fransisco here as well) Did I mention that they finally fixed the keyboard? A public beta (which I have signed up for) will be available in July.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Apple Watch (watchOS 2.0)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developers can now develop native apps for the Apple Watch. This should allow for better access to watch features and speed improvements. Developers can also develop &amp;#39;complications&amp;#39;, which are custom modules for the modular watch faces. You can play with the new Watch Kit API by downloading the latest Xcode 7 beta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itun.es/us/k5SW7.l&quot;&gt;Swift (My Favorite Programming Language)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is my favorite part. Swift 2.0 was announced at WWDC. It adds a lot of new language features as well as speed/error message improvements. New features, better error messages, and more speed; what can be better than that? How about it being OPEN SOURCE! (insert the sound of my mind being blown) By the end of the year Swift 2 will be made available open source. It will run on OS X and Linux. Being that it is open source, I&amp;#39;m sure that someone will port the compiler over to Windows eventually. The new language features include an error handling model, the new guard statement, and syntax improvements.&lt;b&gt; There is so much new in Swift 2.0 that I plan on making a separate blog post just for it.&lt;/b&gt; If you are curious you can download &lt;a href=&quot;https://itun.es/us/k5SW7.l&quot;&gt;the Swift Programming Language Book on iBooks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;As you may (or may not) know, WWDC was on the 10th and introduced many new interesting things for both developers and users. I don&#39;t go super in depth on Swift 2.0 and all the new developer stuff, because that will be covered in my next blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/WWDC/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/WWDC/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to My Blog!</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;The goal of this blog is to &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;share my experiences and thoughts about programming. Some blog posts may blur into productivity or tips I come across. No matter the topic, I promise to keep it interesting and relevant. At the start of this blog you can expect many rapid posts as I have a lot of thoughts brewing being that Google I/O and WWDC, two major developer events, just recently took place. Posts will most likely thin out though over time. Needless to say, bookmark this page and stop by once a week!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;The goal of this blog is to &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/Welcome/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/Welcome/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
